http://www.bhrunners.co.uk/privacypolicy

WelcomeAnnouncementsCalendarFirst TimersHow Do I Join?Contact UsPrivacy Policy
Our EthosClub HistoryClub SessionsFirst TimersWalking GroupCovid RestrictionsBeginners’ and Improvers’ GroupsDevelopment & Performance GroupsTrack NightsDaytime Running GroupClub EventsTestimonialsMembershipNewslettersClub KitJunior Athletics AcademyJunior Academy Coaching TeamWelfareHealth & SafetyCoaches GalleryJunior Academy Coaching TeamTraining AreaTraining - GeneralFuelling - GeneralStrength & ConditioningS&C WorkoutWarm UpPaceShoesHydration & ElectrolytesTraining - Marathon SpecificSample Marathon SchedulesMarathon BiographiesFuelling - Marathon SpecificRecovery - Why? & How?Stride Length & CadenceBlood Donation and RunningGood Posture, Good FormRunning DrillsWhat Causes Stress Fractures?Rate of Perceived EffortTraining Run PurposeInjury Advice ResourceClub AwardsClub ChampionshipBlackcap HandicapDowns Link RelaySouth Downs Way RelayWest Sussex Fun Run LeagueRace ProfilesClair parkrunSussex Grand PrixGoogle GroupWho's Who GalleryPress Releases 2020Press Releases 2019Press Releases 2018Press Releases 2017Press Releases 2016Press Releases 2015Press Releases 2014Press Releases 2013Press Releases 2012Social EventsClub Scrapbook 2015Club Scrapbook 2014Club Scrapbook 2013Club Scrapbook 2012Club Scrapbook 2011Club Scrapbook 2010Photo AlbumsMembers BlogsResultsWSFRLBHR Championship CupClub RecordsGreen Belt RelayUseful InformationClub CharityPrivacy Policy
268days since Coronavirus
Clair parkrun
Haywards Heath junior parkrun
Privacy Policy
How we use your informationWho we areBurgess Hill Runners and Burgess Hill Runners Junior Athletics Academy.You are giving your information to Burgess Hill Runners. In this Privacy Policy, “Burgess Hill Runners”, ‘we’, ‘us’ and ‘our’ refers to both Burgess Hill Runners and Burgess Hill Runners Junior Athletics Academy, unless otherwise stated.For the purposes of data protection legislation, Burgess Hill Runners is the data controller. Burgess Hill Runners is the owner of www.bhrunners.co.uk and we are committed to protecting your privacy and processing your personal data in accordance with the Data Protection Act (DPA) 1998 up to 24 May 2018 and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) on and from 25 May 2018 (Data Protection Legislation). This Privacy Policy explains how the information we collect about you is used and kept securely. It also explains your right to access your information under Data Protection Legislation.By submitting any information about you and, where applicable, others, you and they consent to its use as set out in this Privacy Policy.What data we will collectWhen you first participate with us, prior to formally becoming a member, we may collect certain information about you which will include your name, date of birth, email address, address, telephone number, the name and telephone numbers of emergency contacts nominated by you, and any relevant medical data you choose to provide us with (known as Initial Data).In becoming a member (and on subsequently renewing your annual membership) with us, we will collect certain information about you which may include your name, date of birth, gender, email address, address, telephone number, name of the England Athletics affiliated Clubs with which you are registered and any coaching or officiating licenses that you may hold (known as Athletics Data). We will also collect the names and telephone numbers of emergency contacts nominated by you. You may also choose to provide us with other information relating to your medical/health (which may be classified as Sensitive Information - see below). We will also record your England Athletics Unique Running Number (URN).For coaches, leaders, officials and other relevant roles, we may collect copies of personal documentation required in connection with the Disclosure and Barring Service (DBS).We may offer additional services, such as specific coaching support or mentoring, as part of which we may invite you to provide us with additional relevant information, e.g. regarding your goals and targets, training, performance, health etc. (known as Support Data).In organising races and other events open to non-members, we may collect personal information as part of the entry process, which may include name, any club affiliation, gender, and date of birth or age category (known as Race Data).  Why we collect itWe will collect and process your data for the purposes of registering you as a member of Burgess Hill Runners and administering the club and club events, and your involvement in the sport.Sensitive informationSome of the information we ask you for may be sensitive personal data, as defined by the Data Protection Act 1998 (such as information about ethnicity or health). We will not use such sensitive personal data about you or others except for the specific purpose for which you provide it. Please ensure that you only provide us with sensitive information about other people with their agreement.Our legal bases for processing your informationWe will process your data on the basis of legitimate interests. The legitimate interests are the interests of registering you as a member; to perform the necessary administration activities of the club and club events; and to administer your involvement in the sport.We will process any Sensitive Information data on the lawful basis of consent. Therefore, we will need your explicit consent to process this data, which we will ask for at the point of collecting it from 5 March 2019 onwards.How we use your informationWe will only use your data for these purposes:Creating and maintaining a membership record via Google Sheets and storing it in a secure Google Drive.Transferring members’ names and date of birth to our online register via Google Sheets for registration purposes at club training sessions.Sharing data in accordance with this Privacy Policy, including the transfer of data to England Athletics via an online portal to register members as affiliated members of England Athletics.Maintaining a secure online link via Google Drive via which a restricted number of club officers can access data to use in registering members at club events and competitions and to help to respond to queries, update data and perform necessary administration activity.Maintaining a secure online link via Google Drive via which  a restricted number of club officers can view emergency contact and disclosed medical data in the event of an incident/accident.Regular monitoring of trends in attendance at club training sessions to allow us to make informed operational decisions and create reports for the executive committee to assess the growth of the club. This relies on the regular transfer of data from the online register to a separate reporting sheet where data can be analysed and interrogated by a select number of club officers via a secure online link via Google Drive.As part of the procedure for club coaches, leaders, officials and other relevant roles to obtain clearance under DBS, collecting copies of personal documents required to provide proof of identity, and collecting copies of such DBS certificates and other safeguarding documents and certificates, and storing them in a secure Google Drive.Providing relevant and necessary information to you via email*, text, post:to notify you about club eventsto notify you about recent or upcoming club activityto update you on changes to planned club events and activity.  *This may include adding your email address to our Google Group(s) and sharing your personal contact information (email or telephone) with club officers or coaches to allow them to contact you regarding club related activityCreating and maintaining a record of information, including coaching and other relevant qualifications and expiry dates, groups coached, and mobile and email contact data, for club coaches and leaders via Google Sheets (“BHR Coaches”) and storing it in a secure Google Drive.Maintaining a secure online link via Google Drive via which club coaches and leaders can view and update their information on BHR Coaches.Creating and maintaining a record of information, including Support Data, for those members who have expressly requested additional coaching support and mentoring (“BHR Mentoring”).Maintaining a secure online link via Google Drive via which club coaches and leaders and other relevant club officers can view and update BHR Mentoring.Using Race Data to produce results for races and other events we organise.Sharing your dataWe may share your Athletics Data or Race Data with athletics partners such as England Athletics, Sussex Athletics, Sussex Road Racing Grand Prix and West Sussex Fun Run League, and any third-party data managers that we appoint as data processors as part of administering your involvement in the club. We will share only what is needed for those purposes and, where possible, will anonymise the data before sharing.We may also share your personal information with the police and other law enforcement agencies for the purposes of crime prevention or detection.We will not transfer your data to any other third parties without obtaining your consent.We will not share your data with third parties for marketing purposes.We will also not share any other personal data you provide to us that is not Athletics Data.Protecting your informationOther than as stated in this Privacy Policy, the data that we collect from you will not be transferred to a destination external to Burgess Hill Runners.We will not transfer your data outside of the European Economic Area.We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.How long we will keep itWe will retain your data for such time as you continue to participate with us and/or you are an athlete registered with us, and will then delete your information on a staged basis as follows:Type of dataDate of deletionInitial DataIf you don’t become a member with Burgess Hill Runners, no later than 15 months after the end of the Calendar year in which the Initial Data was collected (unless we have reason to believe you may continue to participate with us in the future, in which case no later than 3 months from when we cease to have reason to believe you may continue to participate with us)Athletics Data; data related to emergency contacts and medical/health data; personal documents required to provide proof of identity for DBS purposes, and copy DBS certificates and other safeguarding certificates and documentation; Support DataNo later than 15 months after the expiry of your annual membership with Burgess Hill Runners (unless we have reason to believe you may continue to participate with us in the future, in which case no later than 3 months from when we cease to have reason to believe you may continue to participate with us)Date of birth; gender; URN; postcode; ethnicity and disabilityIf retained beyond the periods set-out above, this  information will be anonymised and may then be retained indefinitelyRace DataMay be retained indefinitelySocial MediaWe have a number of Social Media platforms, including Facebook and Twitter, which members (and others) are free to join. If you join one of these, please note that the provider of these Social Media platforms have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept responsibility or liability for their policies. Please check their policies before submitting any personal data on our Social Media platforms.Your rightsYou have the following rights under Data Protection Legislation:1. to access a copy of the information comprised in your personal data;2. to object to processing of your personal data that is likely to cause or is causing damage or distress;3. to prevent processing for direct marketing;4. to object to decisions being taken by automated means;5. in certain circumstances, to have inaccurate personal data rectified, blocked, erased or destroyed; and6. to claim compensation for damages caused by a breach of Data Protection Legislation.Finding out what information Burgess Hill Runners holds about youUnder Data Protection Legislation, you can ask to see any personal information that we hold about you. Such requests are called subject access requests. If you would like to make a subject access request, please contact our Data Protection Liaison Officer (see below). You will also need to provide two forms of identification, for example, driving licence, utility bill or passport and, if appropriate, any particulars about the source or location of the information you are requesting.ComplaintsIf you have any concerns or complaints in relation to how Burgess Hill Runners collects and/or processes your personal data, you should contact our Data Protection Liaison Officer (see below) in the first instance. If you are dissatisfied with how your concern/complaint is dealt with by Burgess Hill Runners, you have the right to report your concern/complaint to the Information Commissioner’s Office (www.ico.org.uk).How to contact usIf you have any questions, or you would like to find out more about this notice you can write to:Data Protection Liaison Officer / Club ChairmanBurgess Hill Runners7 Curf WayBurgess HillWest SussexRH15 0GDYou may also contact us using any of the following:Facebook Page: www.facebook.com/burgesshillrunnersFacebook "Closed" Group: www.facebook.com/groups/28439219225/General Enquiries: Email: burgesshillrunners@gmail.comClub Chairman: Email: bhrchair@gmail.comMembership Secretary/Membership Enquiries: Email: bhrmemsec@gmail.comJunior Athletics Academy Enquiries: Email: bhracademymem@gmail.comClub Welfare Officer: Email: bhrwelfareofficer@gmail.comChanges to our Privacy PolicyWe regularly review our Privacy Policy and updates will appear on this page when necessary. This Privacy Policy was last updated on 5 March 2019.
Comments
Burgess Hill Runners accepts no responsibility or liability for opinions or information given by its members on any of our Social Media accounts, be that our website, Google Groups, Twitter or Facebook. Such opinions or information and its provenance remain the responsibility of the author and not Burgess Hill Runners
Sign in|Report Abuse|Print Page|Powered By Google Sites
